[
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "One major objective of Social Studies in Nigeria is to help learners’ ____",
      "options": [ "memorize foreign cultures",
         "understand and solve social problems",
         "avoid participation in society",
         "depend on others for ideas"
      ],
      "answer": "understand and solve social problems"
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "The family can best be described as __________.",
      "options": [ "a group of unrelated people living together",
         "people who come together to form an association",
         "a group of people related by blood, marriage, or adoption",
         "friends from the same village"
      ],
      "answer": "a group of people related by blood, marriage, or adoption"
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "Family bonding means __________.",
      "options": [ "fighting among family members",
         "the act of sharing love, care, and togetherness in the family",
         "avoiding relatives and friends",
         "separating family members from one another"
      ],
      "answer": "the act of sharing love, care, and togetherness in the family"
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "Which of the following is not a function of the family?",
      "options": [ "Provision of love and security",
         "Teaching good behavior and morals",
         "Producing and selling goods for profit",
         "Meeting basic needs such as food and shelter"
      ],
      "answer": "Producing and selling goods for profit"
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "One type of family bonding is __________ bonding.",
      "options": [ "economic",
         "emotional",
         "political",
         "social media"
      ],
      "answer": "emotional"
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "A major advantage of living together as a family is that it __________.",
      "options": [ "brings misunderstanding among members",
         "promotes love, unity, and cooperation",
         "increases loneliness and isolation",
         "reduces communication among relatives"
      ],
      "answer": "promotes love, unity, and cooperation"
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "A good family reputation means __________.",
      "options": [ "the family is feared by neighbors",
         "members behave well and are respected in society",
         "the family hides their problems",
         "the family is very rich"
      ],
      "answer": "members behave well and are respected in society"
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "The importance of a good family reputation includes __________.",
      "options": [ "bringing shame to the family",
         "causing hatred among relatives",
         "earning respect and trust from others",
         "creating conflict in society"
      ],
      "answer": "earning respect and trust from others"
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "One main purpose of marriage is to __________.",
      "options": [ "show off wealth",
         "raise and train children",
         "gain property and fame",
         "separate from one’s parents"
      ],
      "answer": "raise and train children"
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "The three main types of marriage in Nigeria are __________.",
      "options": [ "Civil, Traditional, and Religious",
         "Political, Legal, and Social",
         "Economic, Cultural, and Tribal",
         "Public, Secret, and Formal"
      ],
      "answer": "Civil, Traditional, and Religious"
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "One of the main objectives of Social Studies is to help students ______",
      "options": [ "become responsible citizens in society",
         "focus only on personal success",
         "avoid interaction with others",
         "depend on foreign culture"
      ],
      "answer": "become responsible citizens in society"
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "Which of the following is not a type of marriage practiced in Nigeria?",
      "options": [ "Traditional marriage",
         "Civil marriage",
         "Religious marriage",
         "Political marriage"
      ],
      "answer": "Political marriage"
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "A traditional marriage in Nigeria is usually conducted __________.",
      "options": [ "in a government office",
         "according to the customs of a particular ethnic group",
         "in a church only",
         "by a court judge"
      ],
      "answer": "according to the customs of a particular ethnic group"
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "In civil marriage, couples are joined together __________.",
      "options": [ "in a law court or registry",
         "at the market square",
         "through a religious leader",
         "by family elders"
      ],
      "answer": "in a law court or registry"
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "Religious marriage is conducted according to the teachings of _______",
      "options": [ "schools",
         "religious faiths such as Christianity or Islam",
         "the local government",
         "political parties"
      ],
      "answer": "religious faiths such as Christianity or Islam"
    },
    {
      "number": 16,
      "question": "One purpose of marriage is to __________.",
      "options": [ "enable couples to live happily and raise children",
         "show superiority over others",
         "acquire property from in-laws",
         "create conflict among families"
      ],
      "answer": "enable couples to live happily and raise children"
    },
    {
      "number": 17,
      "question": "Readiness for marriage means __________.",
      "options": [ "being prepared mentally, emotionally, and financially for married life",
         "getting married at a very young age",
         "obeying one’s friends’ advice on marriage",
         "rushing into marriage for money"
      ],
      "answer": "being prepared mentally, emotionally, and financially for married life"
    },
    {
      "number": 18,
      "question": "A person who lacks readiness for marriage may __________.",
      "options": [ "enjoy peace and harmony",
         "have frequent quarrels and misunderstanding",
         "have a stable home",
         "show love and patience"
      ],
      "answer": "have frequent quarrels and misunderstanding"
    },
    {
      "number": 19,
      "question": "Which of the following is a sign of readiness for marriage?",
      "options": [ "Ability to handle responsibilities",
         "Laziness and dependence on parents",
         "Lack of patience and understanding",
         "Fear of commitment"
      ],
      "answer": "Ability to handle responsibilities"
    },
    {
      "number": 20,
      "question": "A person who gets married without emotional maturity is likely to _____",
      "options": [ "have a successful marriage",
         "face challenges in communication and understanding",
         "live peacefully with others",
         "show respect to their partner"
      ],
      "answer": "face challenges in communication and understanding"
    },
    {
      "number": 21,
      "question": "One unhealthy marriage practice in Nigeria is __________.",
      "options": [ "early or forced marriage",
         "mutual respect between partners",
         "open communication",
         "proper family planning"
      ],
      "answer": "early or forced marriage"
    },
    {
      "number": 22,
      "question": "Marriage should be entered into mainly for __________.",
      "options": [ "love and companionship",
         "financial gain",
         "revenge on others",
         "fame and popularity"
      ],
      "answer": "love and companionship"
    },
    {
      "number": 23,
      "question": "Lack of readiness in marriage can lead to __________.",
      "options": [ "happy family life",
         "divorce and broken homes",
         "strong family bonds",
         "peaceful relationships"
      ],
      "answer": "divorce and broken homes"
    },
    {
      "number": 24,
      "question": "Which of the following promotes a healthy marriage?",
      "options": [ "Good communication and understanding",
         "Violence and intimidation",
         "Lack of trust",
         "Dishonesty"
      ],
      "answer": "Good communication and understanding"
    },
    {
      "number": 25,
      "question": "Unhealthy marriage practices can be avoided by __________.",
      "options": [ "proper counseling and preparation before marriage",
         "hiding problems from each other",
         "allowing parents to decide partners",
         "rushing into marriage"
      ],
      "answer": "proper counseling and preparation before marriage"
    },
    {
      "number": 26,
      "question": "Integrity means _______.",
      "options": [ "Stealing from others",
         "Pretending to be good",
         "Cheating in examinations",
         "Being honest and having strong moral principles"
      ],
      "answer": "Being honest and having strong moral principles"
    },
    {
      "number": 27,
      "question": "A person of integrity is one who _______.",
      "options": [ "Lies frequently",
         "Keeps promises and tells the truth",
         "Cheats in business",
         "Disobeys the law"
      ],
      "answer": "Keeps promises and tells the truth"
    },
    {
      "number": 28,
      "question": "One of the benefits of integrity in society is _______.",
      "options": [ "Peace and unity",
         "Distrust among people",
         "Increase in crime",
         "Corruption"
      ],
      "answer": "Peace and unity"
    },
    {
      "number": 29,
      "question": "Integrity can be promoted by _______.",
      "options": [ "Dishonesty",
         "Disobeying laws",
         "Taking bribes",
         "Upholding truth and fairness"
      ],
      "answer": "Upholding truth and fairness"
    },
    {
      "number": 30,
      "question": "Contentment means _______.",
      "options": [ "Being satisfied with what one has",
         "Wanting everything others have",
         "Being greedy",
         "Jealousy and envy"
      ],
      "answer": "Being satisfied with what one has"
    },
    {
      "number": 31,
      "question": "One who is contented will not _______.",
      "options": [ "Steal",
         "Be grateful",
         "Be happy",
         "Live peacefully"
      ],
      "answer": "Steal"
    },
    {
      "number": 32,
      "question": "Lack of contentment can lead to _______.",
      "options": [ "Joy and honesty",
         "Peace of mind",
         "Stealing and corruption",
         "Faithfulness"
      ],
      "answer": "Stealing and corruption"
    },
    {
      "number": 33,
      "question": "A good way to show contentment is to _______.",
      "options": [ "Borrow things you cannot repay",
         "Envy your friends",
         "Be thankful for what you have",
         "Cheat in exams"
      ],
      "answer": "Be thankful for what you have"
    },
    {
      "number": 34,
      "question": "Discipline means _______.",
      "options": [ "Disobeying teachers",
         "Obedience to rules and regulations",
         "Laziness",
         "Doing whatever one likes"
      ],
      "answer": "Obedience to rules and regulations"
    },
    {
      "number": 35,
      "question": "A disciplined student will _______.",
      "options": [ "Come late to school",
         "Obey school rules",
         "Fight in class",
         "Refuse to do homework"
      ],
      "answer": "Obey school rules"
    },
    {
      "number": 36,
      "question": "Discipline helps in building _______.",
      "options": [ "A disorganized society",
         "Order and progress",
         "Laziness",
         "Corruption"
      ],
      "answer": "Order and progress"
    },
    {
      "number": 37,
      "question": "Parents and teachers promote discipline by _______.",
      "options": [ "Rewarding bad behavior",
         "Encouraging lies",
         "Ignoring misconduct",
         "Setting good examples"
      ],
      "answer": "Setting good examples"
    },
    {
      "number": 38,
      "question": "Indiscipline is _______.",
      "options": [ "Disobedience to rules and regulations",
         "Obedience to authority",
         "Hard work and honesty",
         "Being punctual"
      ],
      "answer": "Disobedience to rules and regulations"
    },
    {
      "number": 39,
      "question": "Which of the following is an example of indiscipline?",
      "options": [ "Respecting elders",
         "Obeying traffic rules",
         "Fighting in public",
         "Paying attention in class"
      ],
      "answer": "Fighting in public"
    },
    {
      "number": 40,
      "question": "One major cause of indiscipline is _______.",
      "options": [ "Good parenting",
         "Honesty",
         "Respect for law",
         "Poor home training"
      ],
      "answer": "Poor home training"
    },
    {
      "number": 41,
      "question": "Indiscipline in schools can lead to _______.",
      "options": [ "Peace and order",
         "Academic failure",
         "Respect and progress",
         "High moral values"
      ],
      "answer": "Academic failure"
    },
    {
      "number": 42,
      "question": "Courage means _______.",
      "options": [ "Running away from challenges",
         "Facing difficulties with confidence",
         "Being afraid to speak the truth",
         "Keeping quiet when things go wrong"
      ],
      "answer": "Facing difficulties with confidence"
    },
    {
      "number": 43,
      "question": "A courageous person is one who _______.",
      "options": [ "Lies to save himself",
         "Avoids taking responsibility",
         "Stands for the truth even in danger",
         "Fears what others will say"
      ],
      "answer": "Stands for the truth even in danger"
    },
    {
      "number": 44,
      "question": "Courage helps citizens to _______.",
      "options": [ "Defend what is right",
         "Submit to corruption",
         "Keep silent in injustice",
         "Run away from problems"
      ],
      "answer": "Defend what is right"
    },
    {
      "number": 45,
      "question": "A good example of courage is _______.",
      "options": [ "A student reporting a cheating classmate",
         "A person who lies to avoid punishment",
         "A thief who runs from police",
         "A lazy student copying in exams"
      ],
      "answer": "A student reporting a cheating classmate"
    },
    {
      "number": 46,
      "question": "Nigeria became a federation in _______.",
      "options": [ "1954",
         "1960",
         "1963",
         "1999"
      ],
      "answer": "1954"
    },
    {
      "number": 47,
      "question": "A federation is a system of government in which _______.",
      "options": [ "Power is shared between central, state and local governments",
         "Only one government exists",
         "The army rules",
         "The president has all powers"
      ],
      "answer": "Power is shared between central, state and local governments"
    },
    {
      "number": 48,
      "question": "Nigeria has how many states?",
      "options": [ "30",
         "35",
         "36",
         "37"
      ],
      "answer": "36"
    },
    {
      "number": 49,
      "question": "The three tiers of government in Nigeria are _______.",
      "options": [ "Civil, Military, and Police",
         "Central, Regional, and Municipal",
         "Executive, Legislative, and Judicial",
         "Federal, State, and Local Government"
      ],
      "answer": "Federal, State, and Local Government"
    },
    {
      "number": 50,
      "question": "The main reason for Nigeria’s federal system is to _______.",
      "options": [ "Concentrate power in the center",
         "Cause division among tribes",
         "Make one region rule others",
         "Promote unity in diversity"
      ],
      "answer": "Promote unity in diversity"
    }
  ]


